A Guide to the Sullivan Family Papers 1800-1957
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Sullivan Family Papers 1800-1957
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms56-001
2 cu. ft.
Nineteenth century tax records and personal correspondence of the Sullivan family of Christiansburg, Virginia
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Sullivan Family Papers were received from the estate of Mary Maude Sullivan of Christiansburg, Virginia on April 5, 1956, and the collection was processed, arranged and described in 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
Members of the Sullivan family include T.E. Sullivan, a licensed attorney; C.W. Sullivan, treasurer of Montgomery County; A.O. Sullivan, paymaster to the Virginia House of Delegates; Reverend J.O. Sullivan, the president of the Stonewall Jackson Institute in Abingdon, Virginia; Miss Lake V. Sullivan, a teacher at the Stonewall Jackson Institute and principal of Stuart Female College; and Mary Maude Sullivan, from whose estate the papers originated.
Scope and Content
The Sullivan Family Papers (1800-1957) are comprised of tax books and receipts, personal letters, brochures, souvenirs, photographs, tax books and ledgers. The tax books and receipts series contains large ledger size sheets, tax receipts and tickets for Montgomery County. The personal correspondence series contains letters and postcards addressed to Miss Lake V. Sullivan from various family members and friends. The brochures, souvenirs and photographs series contains many miscellaneous materials relating to the Sullivan family. The ledgers and tax books series contains a book of tax tickets for the Blacksburg tax district; A.O. Sullivan's Pay-master ledger book for the Constitutional Convention; C.W. Sullivan's Bank Book for the Farmers National Bank in Salem, Virginia and the Montgomery Savings Bank; A.O. Sullivan's Pay-roll book for the Virginia House of Delegates; and Lorentz and Sullivan's mill ledger books for Blacksburg, Virginia district taxes.
Description of Series
TAX TICKETS AND RECEIPTS, 1800-1902 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
This series is comprised of various tax receipts and tax tickets from Montgomery County and the state of Virginia. The tickets are arranged by the type of ticket and then chronologically.
PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1883-1889 (Box 1, Folder 7)
This set of the series is comprised of the personal correspondence of Miss Lake V. Sullivan which is arranged chronologically.
BROCHURES, SOUVENIRS AND PHOTOGRAPHS, 1860-1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
This series is comprised of various brochures, souvenirs and photographs, and is not arranged.
LEDGERS AND TAX BOOKS, 1882-1902 (Box 2)
This series is comprised of tax books and ledgers and is not arranged.
Contents List
- Sullivan Family Papers 1800-1957
  - Tax Books and Receipts 1872-1902
    - Tax Tickets and large size ledger sheets 1873 (Box-folder 1-1)
    - Receipts from the Commonwealth of Virginia Office of the Auditor of Public Accounts 1871-1888 (Box-folder 1-2)
    - Tax Receipt Book for Blacksburg, Virginia 1877-1884 (Box-folder 1-3)
    - State tax and State school tax receipt book, 1881-1885; License report for distillers and bar room dealers, November 1880; Liquor Law license returns May 1800-November 1880. 1800-1885 (Box-folder 1-4)
    - State, personal and local tax receipts 1883-1902 (Box-folder 1-5)
    - Written recording of the "yeas" and "nays" of Virginia House of Delegates Session 1891-1892 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Personal Correspondence 1883-1889
    - Correspondence addressed to Miss Lake V. Sullivan 1883-1889 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Brochures, Souvenirs and Photographs 1860-1957
    - A brochure on Montgomery County; a souvenir of the Williams Jennings Bryant addressed to the Virginia Legislature (1884); Brochures of the Stonewall Jackson Institute (1884); Railway Express receipts signed by T.E. Sullivan; Newspaper clippings for family wedding and death announcements. 1860-1957 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Ledgers and Tax Books 1882-1902 (Box 2)
    Ledgers and Tax Books
    Lorentz and Sullivan Mill Ledger, 1882-1884
    Book of Tax Tickets for the Blacksburg tax district, 1885
    A.O. Sullivan Pay-Master Constitutional Convention, 1901-1902
    A.O. Sullivan's Pay-roll book for the Virginia House of Delegates, 1891-1892
    C.W. Sullivan's Bank Book for the Farmers National Bank in Salem, Virginia and the Montgomery Savings Bank, 1884